<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Paul May</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <icon></icon>
  <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.paulmay.org/feed.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org"/>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Ayrton Senna in Flow</title>
      <published>2012-12-01T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8480/8235583569_edc746d19e_o.gif&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;An animated gif showing a POV shot from Ayrton Senna's formula 1 racing car during the 1988 Monaco Grand Prix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the documentary &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1424432/&quot;&gt;Senna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Ayrton Senna describes his mental state during the 1988 Monaco Grand Prix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That day I suddenly realised that I was no longer driving it conscious, and I was in a different dimension for me. The circuit for me was a tunnel, which I was just going, going going…and I realised I was well beyond my conscious understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since watching the film this morning I've been thinking about human-machine interfaces (for the first time in a while). I wonder whether the type of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mihaly_Csikszentmihalyi&quot;&gt;experience&lt;/a&gt; Senna describes requires an interface so simple that it melts into the background. What are the critical ingredients of an experience like this? When is an experience like this undesirable? These aren't new questions, but again - I have haven't thought about them in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Incidentally, in the race Senna built up a substantial lead over Alain Prost before crashing out on the 65th lap. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/ayrton-senna-flow"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/ayrton-senna-flow</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Oliver Sacks is Looking for Indigo</title>
      <published>2012-11-11T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In his talk at The Cooper Union last Friday, Oliver Sacks described his use of hallucinogenic drugs in his search for the colour indigo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were many different motives; it was all a long time ago. It was all between '63 and '67. I had been puzzling about indigo. Indigo was inserted into the spectrum by Newton, so was orange; he felt there should be seven colours as there are seven notes in the musical scale, but it seemed to me that no two people agreed what indigo was like - and it was felt in fact that the pigment derived from the indigo plant was not really indigo. I decided I wanted to see indigo. I couldn't imagine it, but I thought I might be able to hallucinate it so I built a sort of pharmacological launchpad. A base of amphetamine, then some LSD, with a little cannabis on top. It got me fairly pickled; stoned is the right word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I felt ready I said &quot;I want to see indigo &lt;em&gt;now!&lt;/em&gt;&quot; and as if thrown by a paintbrush, a trembling, pear-shaped blob of the most wonderful colour appeared on the wall. &lt;em&gt;Indigo&lt;/em&gt;. It not only seemed wonderfully luminous, but it filled me with a sort of mystical - almost religious joy. I felt it was numinous as well as luminous, and although I'm an old Jewish atheist I thought &quot;this is the colour of heaven&quot; and I thought &quot;this is the colour which Gioto tried to get but never could, and maybe this is a colour that no longer exists on the earth&quot;. And I leant forward in a sort of ecstasy and it vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt very heartbroken, and in fact for months afterwards I would turn over little stones and things. I was looking for indigo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did experience it once again and that was when I came to New York in '65 I went to a concert in the Metropolitan Museum of Art in the Egyptology gallery and in the first half of the concert there was some Monteverdi which transported me and it was sort of rapture. In the interval I wandered into the Egyptology gallery and saw there was some &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lapis_lazuli&quot;&gt;lapis lazuli&lt;/a&gt; amulets and so-forth and some of them were indigo and I thought &quot;thank god - it exists in the world&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second half of the concert I didn't like the music much. I became a little bored and irritable, I thought I'd go and get a sip of indigo, but when I went back the lapis lazuli was just blue and mauve and puce and I've never seen indigo again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He finished the story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew it would have to be a blue of some sort. So I pre-determined it. I didn't say I want to see indigo and then see a splotch of orange. So I played a part, then it took this leap, helped by the launchpad, from imagination to hallucination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally I'm not recommending the experience, although if you can get it from music, or from falling in love, or from medication, or from scenery - that's really a much better way. I'm glad I survived my drug period, many of my friends didn't.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/oliver-sacks-is-looking-for-indigo"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/oliver-sacks-is-looking-for-indigo</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>John Hockenberry Introduces Oliver Sacks at the World Science Festival</title>
      <published>2012-11-10T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of seeing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oliversacks.com/&quot;&gt;Dr. Oliver Sacks&lt;/a&gt; in conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Hockenberry&quot;&gt;John Hockenberry&lt;/a&gt; at the Cooper Union last night. Sacks was speaking about his latest book &lt;em&gt;Hallucinations&lt;/em&gt; as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldsciencefestival.com/webcasts/sacks?/events/sacks&quot;&gt;World Science Festival&lt;/a&gt;. It was a really great event, not least because of John Hockenberry's stunning introduction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tonight we're going to explore this notion of hallucinations. There's a really young crowd here. I hasten to say don't try this at home but I suspect many of you have. Oh well. Be that as it may. Let me tell you a little hallucination story here in this hall, where we might even get a glimpse of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nps.gov/liho/historyculture/summary.htm&quot;&gt;Abraham Lincoln&lt;/a&gt; if we're lucky. All of New York this week is something of a hallucination. My neighborhood looks like Gaza. We're experiencing a sense of perceptual distortion from our encounters with the natural world this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you about a young fellow who studied mathematics at the University of Chicago a couple of decades ago who had a predisposition for psilocybin mushrooms in the course of his mathematical studies and was on a trip, hitchhiking across the country, and got in a car with some lovely individuals who said &quot;look we're driving straight through to Massachusetts and here we've got these amphetamines that are keeping us awake, why don't you stay awake with us?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got in the back seat of the car, we took these strange pills but alas the pills did not do what they were supposed to for the driver and at a certain point in Pennsylvania she drove off the road and went down a 200 foot embankment. I was in the back seat of that car and when I came to consciousness, a few moments after the car reached the bottom of the hill, I realized that I was probably paralyzed for life and was staring through the shattered windshield of a Chevrolet Nova up at a beautiful blue sky, bleeding from a skull fracture and serious set of internal injuries and the blood from the injuries to my head were seeping into the area around my eyes and my eyes were turning completely red and I was looking at the world through this strange blood-filter. I could see clearly, and all of a sudden as I looked through this shattered windshield I could see not the sky anymore, I could see this automobile and there was this sad young man in the car and there were ambulance crews trying to saw this car in half and I looked down and though &quot;oh that's a terrible situation - what's going on? I hope that fellow is alright&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I watched for a while and it was terribly noisy and I was feeling very relieved that I was far away from that mess and I stared at it for a while, and all of a sudden the view began to get a little dark and everything sort of rushed like the sound of a train and all of a sudden I realized that I was the person in the car and they had in fact managed to saw the roof off of the car and pull me to safely. I lost consciousness at that point and woke up in a recovery room in a hospital days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what happened? What was going on in my brain during this event, because I remember it vividly, vividly and can recall precisely what I was looking at from down in the trees, down on what was happening to me, something I couldn't actually have possibly seen because I was in the vehicle. Was it just some &quot;spiritual - whoa - intense experience&quot; or does it reveal something fundamental about the organization of the brain? That's what we're going to explore tonight and we certainly have, as you already heard, the best person on planet Earth to help explore it with us. He's an author, scholar, doctor, clinician, professor and in many ways the pre-eminent storyteller of the brain. Please welcome Doctor, Professor, friend; Oliver Sacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm going to blog about Dr. Sacks' talk separately, but I wanted to highlight Hockenberry's introduction. It really was quite something.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/john-hockenberry-introduces-oliver-sacks"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/john-hockenberry-introduces-oliver-sacks</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>More Flickr Handwringing</title>
      <published>2012-11-09T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-11-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote this as a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stewf.tumblr.com/post/35334085915/flickr-is-dead-long-live-flickr&quot;&gt;Stephen Coles' article&lt;/a&gt; about Flickr and thought it was probably worth snipping and keeping; maybe even expanding upon some time. The crux of Stephen's original article is this paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flickr is certainly not the all-purpose photography social network it once was. There is no doubt Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, and other more immediate, accessible, and — most importantly — mobile-savvy venues took that position. But Flickr is still a haven for professional photography, and for the visual documentation of specialized fields, because nothing is better for tagging, archiving, organizing, research, collaborating, curating, and finding others who share your particular interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see what you're saying, but Flickr is not commercially viable as a place for &quot;professional photographers&quot; (whatever that means anymore). It needs the blend of subscription revenue, mass-participation, exposure to advertising and experimentation that have supported it since it launched. It needs that long tail of people who are trying it out and who might become subscribers. It needs the huge percentage of people who might upload dozens or hundreds of photos, but look at thousands. (For me, the subscription cost is cheap for the value that Flickr offers in isolation, but seemingly expensive when compared to other services.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flickr has always done a good job of focussing on doing a limited number of things really well; sharing, interoperability (its API), privacy, tagging, annotating photographs, the Commons - they designed the state of the art for much of what we take for granted in media sharing on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flickr hasn't responded in any way to the growth of mobile photography - the most significant thing to happen to casual snapping, reportage photography and the aesthetic of photography in decades. The mobile applications it has released have done little more than damage its brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Heather Champ left Flickr efforts to understand and nurture the Flickr community have really withered on the vine. They've lost other, similarly talented folks in design, engineering - these people have found homes in start-ups and more dynamic online services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flickr is becoming a storage device and a community of people who regard themselves as being above the churning sea of content being produced by everyday photographers. It was never designed to be either; it was designed to get as many people as possible (casual and passionate alike) to share photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flickr has lost its way - it's in the expensive mainframe business when the world is buying desktops; it panders to an idealised customer as the actual customer moves on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said all of that, it could come back, it has the potential to come back - but not without taking a good look at how photography actually exists in people's lives today, not what an elite think photography should be - then designing for those needs. It's an exciting prospect, they can do it; I very much hope they do - but time is running out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update, Continuing Conversation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen has &lt;a href=&quot;http://stewf.tumblr.com/post/35334085915/flickr-is-dead-long-live-flickr&quot;&gt;replied to my comment&lt;/a&gt;, he has some good points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I agree that Flickr has modernizing work to do, but I reject the increasingly common assertion that a platform must cater to the lowest common denominator in order to be relevant or successful. There is room on the web for outfits who do certain things very well and leave the rest to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To which I responded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;But here's where we disagree. I look at the photos being snapped by people on their phones and am blown away. I want as many people as possible to take photos, to understand the medium, to really get visual culture. I think Flickr is a great platform for opening up all of that great content and experience to people. I don't see mass participation as lowest common denominator - I see it as an exciting laboratory of culture from which professional photographers have more to learn than fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for whether a service like Flickr needs to be all things to all people - I hear what you're saying, but Flickr was set up to afford particular great things, like sharing - rather than to afford particular groups of people who knew a lot about photography. The fact that the community is becoming less diverse, and pro photographers still find the experience satisfying isn't a surprise. That more serious photographers enjoy feeling like they have an entire web service to themselves now is not surprising - everybody loves a clubhouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photography is the masses' answer to oil painting; and people who have spent a lot of money on cameras feel like it needs to be oil painting again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Flickr can tweak itself, just a bit, so that it reflects camera culture as it exists today then it will be a stronger service, a service more likely to survive financially, pro photographers will have something to learn from and teach to. It's when you get these collisions that you get exciting stuff. The alternative is stagnation and comfort; that's not photography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/more-flickr-handwringing"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/more-flickr-handwringing</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>What Would It Take?</title>
      <published>2012-11-08T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were mostly unaffected by the hurricane - a few trees down in our neighbourhood, a day without internet access, some hassle getting to and from work. We were among the lucky ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some time to cycle around the city last week and the damage is immense; dozens of lives lost, city block after city block in eerie silence, homes and businesses converted into wet piles of debris at the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night as I walked down Mercer Street in a near-blizzard I wondered what it would take to completely destroy a society like this - built around access to technologies like clean water, electric power and reliable heat. Probably not a lot; maybe a storm like Sandy every year, with an off-season punctuated by smaller storms like last night's.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard not to feel insignificant in the face of the sea, the rain, and the wind. We shape our cities and our bodies around the comfortable activities that new technologies afford. The bias of modernity towards comfort leaves us vulnerable when comfort is not the priority - when living becomes coping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thankful that we were unaffected, and thankful for being given a tiny glimpse of what hardship actually looks like. I get the feeling that I'll be noodling on the storm and its aftermath for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/what-would-it-take"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/what-would-it-take</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Bruteforce Democracy</title>
      <published>2012-10-12T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-10-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When the program &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ouah.org/crmi001en.htm&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; the word or combination of random characters that, when lightly encrypted, matched the string in the password file - the computer would beep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd get up from the dinner table and walk to the computer in our living room. I'd see what password this particular user had chosen and how long the program had left to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the next day I would have access to hundreds of UNIX accounts at a nearby university. I would telnet in, look around, then log off. The fun part was over, and being 13 I lacked the imagination to do anything creative, let alone malicious, with the accounts; this was just an incremental step along the path of Lego, magnets, my microscope, a 286, our first modem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last few weeks here in the US I have remembered and thought repeatedly about this long-lost time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's election season, and there is something about the quality of the discourse here that reminds me of brute force password cracking; candidates rapidly cycling through a set of signs in an attempt to elicit a desirable signal. Word, image, emotion out - data, refinement, ballot in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind of the voter is the hashed password, the barrel of a lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home directory, the other side of the door - they are not concerns for today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/bruteforce-democracy"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/bruteforce-democracy</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Lance and Triathlon</title>
      <published>2012-10-11T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-10-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To call today's New York Times article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/11/sports/cycling/lance-armstrong-draws-mixed-reception-from-triathlon-community.html&quot;&gt;Armstrong Finds a Mixed Reception in Triathlon&lt;/a&gt; utterly disingenuous would be putting it mildly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lance Armstrong has been completely banned from the internationally governed (i.e. non-corporate) forms of triathlon because &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyclinginvestigation.usada.org/&quot;&gt;he used drugs to cheat in cycling&lt;/a&gt;. He has taken part in a small number of triathlons that were so desperate for publicity they opted out of the sport's rulebook and insurance coverage to allow him to race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing an equivalence between his official, global ban and his invitation to take part in rogue races is wrong. Saying that this represents &quot;mixed feelings&quot; is shabby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a golfer was caught taking drugs and banned from playing in any tournament that followed the official rules of golf, but was then invited to play big drive, trick shot and crazy golf tournaments, you would call that &lt;em&gt;being banned from golf&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because it's Lance doesn't mean it's complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/lance-triathlon"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/lance-triathlon</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <published>2012-10-03T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently my wife, Cliona, recommended that I put as much effort and thought into my family and friends as I put into my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have turned that advice over and over in my head since then, but have yet to really do anything about it. Change requires action. Action is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/wisdom"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/wisdom</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Finishing Things</title>
      <published>2012-10-03T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-10-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like most people I am better at starting things than I am at finishing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most successful projects I've worked on have been defined by how they are completed. Successful projects seem to flow backwards in time from the desired results, through the phase of making things, to the beginning where we started the journey. (Which reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/10751957&quot; title=&quot;On Perspective&quot;&gt;this great talk&lt;/a&gt; by Charles Leadbeater)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I finished a project; and while it's still fresh in my mind, I wanted to write down some of the loose ends that defined the end of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finishing a Project - A Checklist of Sorts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I stood beside my colleagues and presented the project to a group of people who care about the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We discussed how the impact that the work will have, and how project might be continued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We said thank you to these people, and to the people who have supported us along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;strike&quot;&gt;We celebrated&lt;/span&gt;. I didn't celebrate with the team because my brother was in town, but we'll get together soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I moved moved the documentation and rough-work from the project to a place where people can access it easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I explained what documentation would be most useful in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I archived all the files and documentation related to the project, moving them out of my current projects folder into my completed projects folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I'm now actively thinking about what else I can do to finish projects in a more complete way; finishing in a practical sense, finishing in an emotional sense. By doing this I hope to improve the way that all the work that goes before the finish unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any thoughts or advice for me, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/finishing-things"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/finishing-things</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Clinical Trials Map</title>
      <published>2012-09-19T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the last few months I've been working on design projects with Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center in New York. I've noticed that the medical staff are constantly improving how they work; many patients are enrolled in clinical trials so that new techniques and technologies can be assessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of digging I found that there's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov&quot;&gt;central registry of clinical trials&lt;/a&gt;, including the ones taking place at MSKCC, available online. It's a really interesting dataset; there's a lot of information available about each trial - including the location where each trial is taking place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see what trials are taking place in Brooklyn where I live, and in some other cities around the world, so I wrote a little application that retrieves data from the registry and populates &lt;a href=&quot;http://trials.paulmay.org&quot;&gt; a series of maps&lt;/a&gt;. I'll be working to improve these maps over the next couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://trials.paulmay.org&quot;&gt;Explore the maps&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/paulmmay&quot;&gt;tell me what you think&lt;/a&gt;. If you want more details about how the maps were made, read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All data in the current maps was retrieved on the 16th of September 2012 and will be updated once a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clinical trial data is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov&quot;&gt;clinicaltrials.gov&lt;/a&gt;. My application requests a list of open trials currently accepting new participants taking place in &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?recr=Open&amp;no_unk=Y&amp;cntry1=EU%3AIE&amp;locn=Dublin&amp;displayxml=true&quot;&gt;Dublin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?recr=Open&amp;no_unk=Y&amp;cntry1=ES%3ACN&amp;locn=beijing&amp;displayxml=true&quot;&gt;Beijing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?recr=Open&amp;no_unk=Y&amp;cntry1=EU%3AGB&amp;locn=London&amp;displayxml=true&quot;&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?recr=Open&amp;no_unk=Y&amp;cntry1=EU%3AES&amp;locn=Barcelona&amp;displayxml=true&quot;&gt;Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; or  &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/results?recr=Open&amp;no_unk=Y&amp;cntry1=NA%3AUS&amp;state1=NA%3AUS%3ANY&amp;locn=Brooklyn&amp;displayxml=true&quot;&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt; and a list of studies is returned. Studies with unknown status are not returned. Each study is then &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00463294?displayxml=true&quot;&gt;retrieved individually&lt;/a&gt;. Each study has a number of &quot;facilities&quot; associated with it where the trial is being carried out - the address of these facilities is passed to the Google Maps API which returns location information. The latitude and longitude is used to populate a map made using &lt;a href=&quot;http://leaflet.cloudmade.com/&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;. (I'll be releasing the application on GitHub when I've documented it and cleaned it up a bit.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;caveats&quot;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is just a little experiment&lt;/strong&gt; and the maps aren't offered with any guarantee of completeness, availability, quality or accuracy. You shouldn't use these maps to satisfy anything other than idle curiosity. If you want accurate trial data you should get it directly from &lt;a href=&quot;http://clinicaltrials.gov&quot;&gt;clinicaltrials.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geocoding is inherently flaky&lt;/strong&gt;; if Google Maps couldn't return a lat/lon for the facility where the trial is taking place, that trial is not shown at all. Even when Google Maps did return a lat/lon the location should be treated as approximate. In many cases trials are shown at the center of cities because Google Maps can't identify a more specific location (e.g. because  O'Connell Street in Dublin is returned when you search for &quot;Dublin, Ireland&quot; a lot of clinical trials appear to be taking place on O'Connell street).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Showing lots of markers close to each other on a map is a non-trivial problem&lt;/strong&gt;; at the moment a lot of the little markers that show the position of trials are being drawn on top of each other - this is something I'll try to fix in the next release.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/clinical-trials-map"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/clinical-trials-map</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>