<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Paul May</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <icon></icon>
  <updated>2014-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.paulmay.org/feed.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org"/>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Oxford to Brighton, Weeknotes</title>
      <published>2014-08-18T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2014-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A week of solid progress on work projects; things are starting to get very interesting - that point of a project where big chunks start knitting together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I trained lightly this week. I&#39;m starting to plan ahead for the winter, and have just been trying to keep things ticking over. I&#39;d like to focus on swimming and running this winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week culminated in a long cycle from Oxford to Brighton, and then a lovely weekend in Brighton. The cycle should have been about 160K, but between meandering and free-form navigation, it ended up being 192K door-to-door, and about 7.5 hours on the bike. The journey wasn&#39;t particularly tough on the legs, but the constant navigation was mentally taxing. I was glad to get off the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend in Brighton was very nice; it&#39;s a really interesting town. Charming, hip, and a little faded around the edges; a mix of seaside tack and a graphic designer insurgency. Definitely somewhere I&#39;d like to explore more. We stayed in a lovely &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.co.uk/rooms/1082800&quot;&gt;AirBnB&lt;/a&gt; just outside the town. Highly recommended; incredibly friendly host, wonderful breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else. Took lots of photos, saw people kitesurfing in the middle of a bloody gale. Ate fish and chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/oxford-to-brighton"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/oxford-to-brighton</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Do Anything, Eat Anything</title>
      <published>2014-08-10T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2014-08-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s feen a fun week. I raced &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/london-triathlon-2014-race-notes&quot;&gt;my first triathlon in 5 years&lt;/a&gt; last weekend. As this was my only priority race for the year (I&#39;ll maybe do one other triathlon before focusing on winter training), I&#39;ve allowed myself a week of rest, eating anything I want, doing whatever. It&#39;s been nice. I&#39;ve gained just over 1Kg in a week, which is hilarious and terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the time that I would have spent training fixing up my blog a little. I wanted to try some new typography, and a more flexible structure. The paint is still wet, but I am excited to be rummaging around and trying some new things. I get to prototype things at work quite a bit, but it&#39;s nice to work on my own little place on the web, even if I only have time to make something very simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cliona is doing great. We are now just 10 weeks away from the birth of our first child. We don&#39;t know if it&#39;s going to be a boy or a girl, and as such, haven&#39;t decided on a name, or even a shortlist of names. We&#39;ll probably think more about that over the next few weeks. What&#39;s certain is that the baby is kicking and wriggling around like it can&#39;t wait for the transition to land-mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister-in-law, Michelle, got engaged to her boyfriend Kevin today. My sister-sister, Louise, has started sending out invitations to her own wedding in October. It&#39;s all very lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is going well. My team is really working hard, and solving some very challenging problems. We need more people; so if you&#39;re a software engineer, interaction designer, or otherwise good at building things for the web, please get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather here has started to turn a little chillier, a little gloomier. I want to wring what&#39;s left out of the summer, so this week I&#39;d like to spend some time out on the bike. Hopefully the weather cooperates.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/weeknotes-august-wk2"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/weeknotes-august-wk2</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Triathlon Race Notes</title>
      <published>2014-08-10T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2014-08-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took up triathlon in 2006 on a whim. A work colleague was racing the Chicago Triathlon to raise money for charity, and he wanted others to race with him. I took up the sport, raced in Chicago, and continued to train and race for a couple of years. Having done little sport or exercise before then, finding a sport that I enjoyed was a revalation to me. It had a hugely positive impact on my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In New York, I flirted with the idea of running a marathon. I did more running than I had ever before, but when I tried to ramp up my distance, my ankles and knees gave way, and I was forced to stop all running, and any training involving force or impact on my legs. At first, being injured was depressing and frustrating, not to mention sore. After a while, I got used to it. That was two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January this year, prompted by our move to training-friendly Oxford, I decided to try some regular exercise again. I just tried to get back in shape without putting too much impact on my still-grumbling joints. I joined a triathlon club. I spent quite a bit of time cycling (indoor and outdoor), and got back into the swimming habit. I set myself a goal of completing a triathlon in 2014. Finishing the London Triathlon, a race I did way back in 2007, seemed like a nice, specific target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June, after a few months of good training, I set myself a more specific goal of finishing the race faster than I had in 2007. My time in 2007 was &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/london-city-triathlon-report&quot; title=&quot;2007 London Triathlon Race Report&quot;&gt;2 hours 31 minutes&lt;/a&gt;; not terrible for a race that is roughly international distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the weeks coming up to this year&#39;s race, knowing that I wouldn&#39;t be able to coast on the energy of my 20&#39;s, I made a very detailed race plan, based on a template described by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Triathletes-Training-Bible-Joe-Friel/dp/1934030198/&quot; title=&quot;The Triathlete&#39;s Training Bible&quot;&gt;Joe Friel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I would actually race, rather than just aim to finish. I wouldn&#39;t set out to race other people, but I&#39;d push as hard as I could. This might sound obvious, but when I raced before, my only real thought was to finish - never to push hard, or hit a specific set of goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set a goal time for the whole race of 2 hours 30 minutes. I knew that this was feasible at a stretch, based on my training times. I set secondary goals for each segment of the race. Setting secondary goals was really a new idea to me, but it makes a lot of sense. The thinking goes that if you get a puncture on the bike, you are probably not going to make your goal for the whole race. You might still run a good 10K, so having that secondary goal to focus on is very positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The target times made up a small part of my race plan. I planned out my race week training and preparation in detail. I planned my diet in the run up to the race, so that I would maintain my weight while my training was tapering down. I planned my activities on the morning of the race, how I&#39;d set up my transition area, and then I made specific notes about each segment of the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the swim, I decided where I&#39;d line up at the start, and what I&#39;d do in each 500m section. For the bike, I decided on a target cadence and heart rate range - things I can control accurately, unlike my speed - which can be hard to maintain in windy weather. For the run, I set a target heart range and a target pace per kilometre, and made notes about my running form - which can get messy when I&#39;m tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read the whole race plan once a day in the week coming up to the race. On the morning of the race I was still nervous, but having the plan took a lot of the stress out of the small decisions; what gear to check, when to eat, what to eat, where to go etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before 3pm, my wave assembled in the Excel Centre, and a few minutes later we were in Victora Basin, starting the swim. The first 500m was rougher than I had thought it was going to be. There was plenty of space to swim, but I wheezed and strained, and felt like I was drowning. I resorted to some breast stroke to get my breath back, and got passed by a lot of guys. Once I passed the first buoy, my lungs opened up and I got into a good rhythm. I stuck close to the inside line, and navigated a straight line to the second turn. I passed a good few people, and got out of the water feeling good. There was a small hiccup when I pulled my timing chip off my leg with my wetsuit; thankfully I noticed, and got it back on again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transition to bike was fairly smooth. For the first time, I attached my shoes to my bike, and tried a rolling mount, albeit at low speed. I got away without a fuss, and got my feet into the shoes after about 100m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really went as hard as I could on the bike, without going into the red. I kept up a high cadence in my target heart range, and thankfully the conditions allowed me to get up to a good speed. I took on about 500ml of energy drink, and two gels on the bike. Unlike previous races, eating on the bike felt essential. I could really feel the difference at the end of the bike; sore, but not out of energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two laps, I pulled into transition, but got confused and wasted time talking to the race marshals. The bike course is a bit shorter than advertised, and this threw me. I spent easily 3 minutes trying to work out if I had missed a segment of the course. I was still thinking about this, and worrying about being disqualified, well into the run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confusion over the bike distance had a negagive impact on the first lap of my run. My concentration had gone a bit, and instead of going out hard in the first lap, I dawdled and paid far too much attention to the pain in my legs. Once I had warmed up my running muscles, the rest of the run was fine. I had plenty of energy in the last lap, and finished strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My time for the race was 2:20:02, nearly 10 minutes inside my target time. Here are some more details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim time: 00:30:34 (1467th overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T1 time: 00:03:34 (269th overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike time: 1:00:23 (126th overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T2 time: 00:03:04 (2028th overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run time: 00:42:29 (700th overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall position: 331st&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gender position: 343rd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Category position (M30-34): 94th out of 827 finishers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On the day I was really thrilled with my time. I am still very happy that I met my goals, but I have a few questions about the length of the bike course on the day, and on reflection, I know that I could have done better in all sections of the race with more training. I&#39;m happy with my age group place, which is decent given the number of participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I&#39;ve spent quite a bit of time thinking back over the race, and have some specific areas to focus on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim start - I need to be much fitter and more efficient on the swim. I don&#39;t need to start quickly, but I can&#39;t struggle in the first 500m. My lungs need to be open and ready within a couple of minutes, not 10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T1 - I need to practice taking my wetsuit off, with specific focus on getting my right ankle out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T1 - I need to get a lot better at mounting the bike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike - I need to think about being more aerodynamic. I need to build up more endurance so that I can cope with tougher conditions, and stay fresh in the last 10-15 monutes of sustained effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run - I need to do more work on the mental side of running, especially off the bike. I am able to run quickly off the bike, but if I&#39;m not feeling confident, I listen to the pain too much. I obviously need to get faster and more efficient as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m hoping that these notes serve me well as I think about doing more races, and face into my first full winter of training in 5 years. I want to keep it fun and challenging, then come back in the Spring with a plan to do more races. I might do London again next year, just to see if I can translate what I learned this year into a better performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than anything, I&#39;m very happy to be back doing a sport I love, after having very nearly thrown in the towel completely. I want to say a special thank you to Cliona who is always there for me when I&#39;m pushing myself, and who gave me amazing support on the day of the race.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-triathlon-2014-race-notes"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-triathlon-2014-race-notes</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Weeknotes, Second Week of 2014</title>
      <published>2014-01-12T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2014-01-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re back in Oxford this week after two weeks in Ireland for Christmas. Things are going well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought myself a little bike to run around Oxford, and this has made getting to and from the gym and pool much easier. I&#39;m back into an exercise routine, and while starting again with swimming is always tough after a long break, I&#39;m happy to be back moving again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last year I&#39;ve been scraping together a dataset from news sources in Ireland. This week I&#39;ve started to pull the data together, and think about projects I&#39;d like to pursue to explore the data. Nothing revolutionary, just some visual and textual analysis of news and published sentiment over the last 12 months; maybe some things similar to my From Over Here project. It&#39;s exciting to have a home-made dataset, rich enough to address from a number of different angles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about the purpose of a blog/personal site is in 2014, and I have arrived at an answer that lives somewhere between lab notebook (demonstrating work done in pursuit of some experiment or other), LEGO box (lots of tiny, pre-made components that can be re-fashioned into different forms), and a sort of public workspace or shop (A place where I am sitting at a bench making something, can gesture to others to look, contribute to others&#39; work - the Shop at ITP basically).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this exploration and thought-process, I&#39;ve started to compile a lot of the data that&#39;s out there in my social networks into my own API, making it much easier for me to incorporate things like tweets, bookmarks, photos and other breadcrumbs I leave around the web into this site and other projects. Once I&#39;ve gathered enough data, I&#39;ll dig into making endpoints, components etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is going well. I will be in New York w/c 20th to meet up with the folks from Sloan-Kettering. I&#39;m looking forward to the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s all for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/weeknotes-jan12"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/weeknotes-jan12</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Final Year Projects at CIID</title>
      <published>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I had the pleasure of attending some of the final student presentations and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/&quot;&gt;end-of-year show&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ciid.dk&quot;&gt;Copenhagen Institute for Interaction Design&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some of my favourite projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5498/11371288085_dc17139d97_b.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Indie Controls&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/indie-controls/&quot;&gt;Indie Controls&lt;/a&gt;: A novel, open-source, modular games controller by Daniel Lahar.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5474/11371288685_808c778bf9_b_d.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Pretotype&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/pretotype/&quot;&gt;Preotype&lt;/a&gt;: A toolkit that supports the design and documentation of physical computing and electronics projects.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3832/11371423703_5fb9cc86b8_b_d.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Griphint&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/griphint/&quot;&gt;Griphint&lt;/a&gt;: A pen that offers autistic children visual feedback on their pen grip as they learn to write.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3710/11371424183_748030805e_b.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Kwerkies&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/kwerkies/&quot;&gt;Kwerkies&lt;/a&gt;: Really beautifully designed wooden toys that operate as a network, and react to one another.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also really liked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/hej_verden/&quot;&gt;hej_verden&lt;/a&gt; - A toolkit to help children learn computer programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/little-treasures/&quot;&gt;Little Treasures&lt;/a&gt; - A thoroughly-designed service designed to teach children about the concept of value and the use of money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/hand-made/&quot;&gt;Hand Made&lt;/a&gt; - An exploration of human hand gestures, and a platform to collect novel hand gestures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The work from CIID students was, as ever, thorough and thoughtful. It&#39;s a great programme.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/ciid-show"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/ciid-show</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Paying for the Web we Need</title>
      <published>2013-12-10T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-12-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I probably reacted to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/edward-snowden&quot;&gt;Edward Snowden&lt;/a&gt; revelations in the same way that a lot of people did. Not with surprise that mass surveillance happens, but that it happens &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/03/world/no-morsel-too-minuscule-for-all-consuming-nsa.html&quot;&gt;so completely and so effectively&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months later, I&#39;ve factored the revelations into my opinion of how governments tend to behave (&lt;em&gt;slightly more competent, a lot less cautious&lt;/em&gt;), but otherwise, my behaviour remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web that I use, and have helped to build, is one where acceptance of minute surveillance of my activities is a pre-condition for the use of the most basic services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This web has laid the technical foundations for mass surveillance, but I believe that it has also laid the psychological/ethical groundwork for the acceptance of surveillance as just another facet of my daily life. (Why &lt;em&gt;wouldn&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; governments put me under surveillance when I&#39;ve accepted that companies are allowed to, in exchange for keeping track of my friends&#39; birthdays.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology introduces biases in the types of things it makes more or less easy. Things that are easy become normal. Things that are difficult become other. The Snowden leaks are the clearest demonstration of this at scale. Remaining private is difficult, and so demanding privacy now would disconnect me from the majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly maybe, the leaks show me that technology has drastically skewed my sense of what is acceptable. I can&#39;t help but fit the NSA&#39;s activities into the moral framework I&#39;ve built up around targeted advertising. And they are certainly not equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;d be impractical, and lonely, to move my online life over to services that aren&#39;t funded via surveillance-marketing, but I can take a small step by paying for more parts of the web that I value in cold hard cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also try to evaluate things that might be technologically similar, but ethically different, with a much more critical eye.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/paying-for-the-web-we-need"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/paying-for-the-web-we-need</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Weeknotes, Colder Weather</title>
      <published>2013-12-06T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-12-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Suddenly it&#39;s December. Work is going well. My home office is quite comfortable, and I have been more productive than I was when working from the local co-working space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my spare time this week I&#39;ve been mapping out some changes I want to make to this site, and planning a few personal projects and longer articles I&#39;d like to complete in 2014. Just sketches and post-its for now, but progress nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My real reason for writing today is that I am in a little bit of a physical activity slump. From training 6 days a week up until August, I now find myself with a gorgeous new racing bicycle, access to the Oxford University gym, and every opportunity to exercise, but no motivation whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of it, no doubt, has to do with being in a new city with absolutely no training buddies to call on. Part of it has to do with the lack of a concrete goal. Part of it has to do with the weather and scant daylight. Part of it has to do with overcoming the inertia of taking a few months off. A big part of it has to due with the accumulation of injuries, and the creeping realisation that I can&#39;t really run anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I realised a few weeks ago that this is the slump that people get into when their body starts to weaken a little, and their legs start to thicken a little. Maybe this is a slump that a lot of people don&#39;t get out of. It certainly feels different from the familiar fraying of good habits I experience before I make an adjustment. I hope that writing about it helps me figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cliona is in New York this weekend, then in California next week. I will be spending some time in Copenhagen, and maybe New York, before heading back to Dublin for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not quite at ease today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/colder-weather"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/colder-weather</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Life in Run Mode</title>
      <published>2013-11-09T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-11-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey there. Things have been settling into a nice routine here in Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have moved into, then out of a local co-working space - and I&#39;m now working out of a little home office. The co-working space was nice, but I&#39;ve been traveling to New York every 4-5 weeks, and it was hard to justify the cost. Working at home has &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/how-to-not-go-insane-while-working-from-home/&quot;&gt;some familiar challenges&lt;/a&gt;, but I&#39;ve done everything I can to make sure that the home office feels comfortable and somewhat separate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a bike, and joined a local cycling club. I haven&#39;t really put many miles into my legs yet - but I am looking forward to getting into the rhythm of weekend spins out in the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cliona is doing well; she bought a car, which has made her commute to work much more manageable. This week she&#39;s in Donegal visiting some colleagues. Next week I&#39;m in New York, then she&#39;s in California. We are both working very hard, and traveling a bit - but we&#39;ll get a break towards the end of the year and Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been thinking about getting a dog for quite a while. It was never really practical in New York, because we knew that our time there was likely to be brief. Now that we&#39;re starting to feel at home in Oxford, and have some more space, we&#39;ve started to look around for an animal-pal. We visited Oxford Animal Sanctuary, and met three lovely dogs. Two of them were great, but too big for us, and one was small, but seemed to be a little on the grumpy side. Anyway, now that we&#39;ve dipped our toes in the water, we&#39;re going to think about the type and size of dog that we can handle, and in the New Year go out and see if we can find that dog. We know that he or she is out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not been taking many photos, mostly because I can&#39;t find a good lab in Oxford. Nowhere, and I mean nowhere that I can find will process black and white. Most places are reluctant to take film at all. Given that I am only shooting on film these days, that&#39;s putting a cramp on things. Anyway, I might need to shoot film, then take day trips to London to get rolls processed. It&#39;s not ideal. Anyway, we&#39;ll see what happens - but I would like to get back to the camera as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&#39;s what&#39;s happening right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/life-in-run-mode"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/life-in-run-mode</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Allentown, New York - Week 10</title>
      <published>2013-09-06T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-09-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3703/9687360957_f2cc742855_b_d.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo silverframe&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Me and Simon taking part in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lehighwheelmen.org/&quot;&gt;2013 Donut Derby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What an amazing week. I&#39;ve been in the US since Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend with Simon, Amy, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/paulmmay/7916834928/&quot;&gt;Trotsky&lt;/a&gt; in Allentown, which was lovely. We ate great food, watched Total Recall &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Predator. Super chilled and fun times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, me and Simon took part in a 36-mile bike race, the Donut Derby. In the Derby, racers have 3 minutes deducted off their time for &lt;a href=&quot;http://lh6.ggpht.com/_qhfpUmZ6R-c/TJBMl7tCk8I/AAAAAAAACzM/loE08IokCEQ/s1600-h/DSCN1439%5B5%5D.jpg&quot;&gt;every donut eaten&lt;/a&gt; at the rest stops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me and Simon managed a total of 6 donuts each. We then managed to get lost - adding 5 miles onto our race, and wiping out both our donut-adjusted time, and our chances of finishing in the respectable half of the field. Next year I am going to pay closer attention to the road markings, bring a GPS device, and eat more donuts. It was still a great ride, and was actually the first time me and Simon have been on bikes together since we were kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I relocated to New York, and spent the working week meeting with the folks at MSKCC. In the evenings I got to spend time with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://fredtruman.com/spring-2011-show-photo&quot;&gt;super-amazing NYC friends&lt;/a&gt;   , eat &lt;a href=&quot;http://newyork.seriouseats.com/2008/06/new-york-citys-top-10-best-ice-cream-sandwiches-nyc.html&quot;&gt;ice-cream sandwiches&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oldebrooklynbagelshop.com/&quot;&gt;eat delicious bagels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/dough-brooklyn&quot;&gt;eat more donuts&lt;/a&gt;, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.armoryonpark.org/programs_events/detail/the_machine&quot;&gt;the theatre&lt;/a&gt;, and see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pianosnyc.com/upstairs&quot;&gt;some great live music&lt;/a&gt;. The whole week was like a highlights reel of everything I love about New York. I didn&#39;t get to see everybody I&#39;d like to see, but I hope to be back soon. Special thanks to Ross and Natalie for letting me stay with them for a couple of nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m at Newark airport now, heading to Dublin via London. Tomorrow I get to see my family and my Dublin friends, attend Kevin Cannon&#39;s birthday, and see Verona Riots in concert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be back at home in Oxford on Sunday night. Maybe on Monday I will not get on a plane, or cross a border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is good at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/nyc-weeknotes-10"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/nyc-weeknotes-10</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Goodbye Hackney</title>
      <published>2013-08-31T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An addendum to &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/everywhere-i-have-ever-lived&quot;&gt;Everywhere I Have Ever Lived&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/goodbye-for-now-new-york&quot;&gt;left New York&lt;/a&gt; in the Summer of 2013, we moved to London. Cliona looked for a new job while I continued to work on projects with Sloan-Kettering from a co-working space in Hackney Wick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sublet a cute little apartment fom &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arcadefinearts.com/artists&#39;%20pages/mariazahle.html&quot;&gt;Maria Zahle&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s our happy Hackney home for two months before Cliona finds a job in Oxford, and we opt to move up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5494/9629486937_b97d0ccfe7_c_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Sandgate House, Hackney, London&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will miss Hackney quite a bit, but new adventures await.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/goodbye-hackney"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/goodbye-hackney</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>