<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Paul May</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <icon></icon>
  <updated>2013-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.paulmay.org/feed.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org"/>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Red Burns</title>
      <published>2013-08-24T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Red Burns, founder of ITP, and true force of nature, died yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met Red during my impromptu interview for ITP. Cliona and I were visiting New York for just one day. We were engaged, and spent the morning buying our wedding rings in the diamond district. We stopped by ITP for a tour with George Agudow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red heard that I was on the floor, and called me into her office. She asked Cliona to come in too, and found a comfortable chair for her to sit in while we talked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;So, I've read your application and I can't make head or tail of it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any idea that this was going to be a casual chat went out the window. She proceeded to grill me for a solid hour about what I had written, why I wanted to come to ITP, what my ideas were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I didn't know exactly why I wanted to come to ITP. I was worried that I was becoming a talker and not a doer. I wanted to make things again. I was interested in health and the human body. Instead of just saying that, I had written thousands of words of the worst sort of bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red called me out, and I had very little to say for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, Cliona and I sat quietly eating a slice of pizza in the corner deli. I was grumpy. How dare she do that in front of my future wife!? Maybe ITP wasn't for me. (Cliona rightly pointed out that I should have expected her to interview me, or at least talk to me, if I was visiting all the way from Ireland).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. I got into ITP. I got to make things again. I got to meet the most wonderful people. I learned and grew more in two years than I had in the previous ten. I got to do all of this thanks to Red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many more encounters with her over the years. She took an interest in some of my projects, and made sure I talked to the right people about them. She was constantly working to make sure that our work was as good as it could be, and had the maximum impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I start to lose my nerve, or I feel myself drifting into excuses, I think of my interview with Red. I summon some of her clarity, and I get myself back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Burns changed my life. Thank you Red.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/red-burns"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/red-burns</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 7</title>
      <published>2013-08-21T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Week 7 blurs into week 8. After a couple of months of very hard work, Cliona has found a great job in Oxford. Oxford is about an hour North of London, so over the next few weeks we'll be moving up there from our temporary digs in Hackney. Today we finished the paperwork for a little house we're going to rent in central Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I'll be back here regularly, I am a little sad to be leaving London. It's a fascinating city, a grubby city, a very real city - different from New York, but sharing a sense of infinite possibility. I have really enjoyed the couple of months here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is going well. We made a couple of significant steps forward on a machine-learning projects last week. I am designing and building some simple, useful little products. Even though we're a long way from finished, I am proud of the work we've done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's all for now. I'll write about our move to Oxford in the coming days and weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-week-7"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-week-7</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 6</title>
      <published>2013-08-09T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3736/9468954440_68c94b0ecb_o.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Marcela and Paul in London by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/22463687@N05/9468954440/&quot;&gt;Cliona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week has flown by in London. This week we've been fortunate enough to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ameliechucky.cl/&quot;&gt;Marcela&lt;/a&gt; staying with us. She's a Chilean who I met in New York who came to London from Switzerland to renew her US visa (nothing is ever simple with US visas). She leaves tomorrow, and we'll miss her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In tangentially-related news, I'll be visiting New York at the beginning of September for work, and also to see family and friends. Plans are still coming together, but I'm looking forward to the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work has been going well. We're slowly ironing out some of the technical issues associated with me doing work for a New York-based hospital. We made a lot of progress this week, thanks to a few key people in New York. I am lucky to work with such great people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cliona is in Dublin this weekend visiting family, and on Sunday I am hoping to catch up with the folks from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.attopartners.com&quot;&gt;Atto&lt;/a&gt; who'll be in town. Can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-week-6"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-week-6</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 5</title>
      <published>2013-08-02T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Busy week. Desire to turn off computer for the evening. All quickies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3815/9384652196_d6cab8217c_o.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Duck Pal&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quickies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last weekend we took a trip to the British Museum. It's astounding. The Rosetta Stone is jawdropping. The number of tourists in the British Museum jostling to get a terrible, flash-lit photograph of the Rosetta Stone is jawdropping, in a very different way. The British Museum is wall to wall loot, and tourists clambering over and photographing said loot in a frenzy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had a very tasty breakfast at Towpath Cafe, then visited Columbia Road Flower Market, and Hackney City Farm (see Duck, above). Gorgeous, gorgeous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cliona has been interviewing for jobs, and has made very good progress - news soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We've been tip-toeing our way through the latest episodes of Breaking Bad. It's so, so, so good. Probably the most compelling TV show I've ever watched.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am making progress with yoga. I am still the sweaty beginner in the class, but I can feel myself getting stronger. Less painful vibration as I hold simple poses. Result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A so-so week at work. Nobody said this was going to be easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-5"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-5</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 4</title>
      <published>2013-07-26T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-07-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week has been pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday/Sunday I completed the Dunwich Dynamo; an overnight bike ride from London to Suffolk. I covered just over 175Km in about 7 hours 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 75Km out of London were refreshing - some stopping and starting, roundabouts, and a few gentle rises to wake up the legs. I was glad to reach the rest stop just after midnight. I took on water and had some very decent food, provided by volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the sun completely gone, but with a bright moon to give a bit of a glow to the roads, I got into a group of cyclists from 75Km to 130km and made good time in their train. It is somewhat surreal to barrel along on quiet country roads in the dead of night, following a trail of blinking red lights that stretches off into the gloom. Just the sound of wheels on the road, and the click-click of my freewheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a little lost between 130Km and 150Km. Thankfully two other cyclists also took the wrong turn, and one of them knew how to get back to the main route. We got back in contact, and settled into the last 20-30Km. A slog. I was tired, and my legs were starting to tighten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I made it to Dunwich beach just after 5am I had a couple of cups of tea, a bar of chocolate, a protein drink. Some people got in for a swim.  I just had a nice sit down. The bus back to London left just after 9am. At home, I ate lunch, had a shower, and proceeded to pass out for several hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dynamo was definitely the highlight of the week, and I'll do it again next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, my work is challenging at the moment - in good ways and bad. Cliona is searching and interviewing for jobs. She is making great progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first full month in London has flown by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quickies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am falling behind in the linear algebra class, and thinking of shelving it for now. I've already learned a lot, and I can come back to it on my own time, or the next time the online class is run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished 1Q84. It's definitely the least coherent and most conventional Murakami book that I've read. Whole sections feel repititious. There's a sort of sappy misogyny about the plot. The resolution feels like an unconvincing magic trick. It's his worst book to date in my opinion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should I read next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've started taking yoga classes, they are very challenging, but I think I am making progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-4"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-4</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 3</title>
      <published>2013-07-19T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent last weekend in Ireland; at a wedding in Longford on the Saturday, and in Dublin on the Sunday. The weather in Ireland is roasting. The country really shines in the sun. The landscape sparkles, people are happy and friendly, and there's a sense of optimism about the place that's sometimes absent in the greyer months. It was a real pleasure to see Ireland at its best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was in Dublin, I got to meet Mr. Jack Holland, newly arrived son of Therese Veale and Derek Holland. He is a dote of the highest order, well-mannered to boot, and his parents were a sight for sore eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to get a spot on a return bus for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://southwarkcyclists.org.uk/news/dunwich-dynamo-xxi-2013-faqs-essentials&quot;&gt;Dunwich Dynamo&lt;/a&gt;, an overnight ride from London to Dunwich, Suffolk. It's 120 miles, or about 200Km. I haven't done a cycle of that length in quite a while, but I'm told it's pretty flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been using the same cycling gear since about 2008, and having left a lot of it in the US, or disposed of it altogether, it was time to get new stuff. I bought myself a new jersey, shorts, helmet, shoes - and some other bits and pieces. Thanks to Alex at Swift Cycles in London for helping me choose and fit the gear properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is going pretty well. Design and development of two products is proceeding nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quickies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My linear algebra practice has being getting scant attention. I am sorry linear algebra gods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am 90% of the way through 1Q84. I don't get a sense that it'll end satisfactorily. I can't say it's been among my favourite Murakami books; it needs a damn good editing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-3"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-3</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 2</title>
      <published>2013-07-12T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-07-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not too much to report this week. I've been continuing to get set up in London, and have been working on some early plans for two new projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight I'm off to Dublin for a flying visit - I'll be in Longford at a wedding tomorrow, then back in Dublin for a few hours on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quickies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought a Windows laptop to use as my work computer. It's ugly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finally bought a scanner that can scan negatives, slides/positives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have not done any of my linear algebra coursework this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am 68% of the way through 1Q84.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-2"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-2</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>London Week 1</title>
      <published>2013-07-05T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a very positive first full week in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we've left New York, I'm going to continue working with Sloan-Kettering from London. I am really delighted about that. My working day in London overlaps with New York by about 4 hours, which is perfect - lots of time for us to collaborate, then lots of time for heads-down work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the the coming year my focus will be on designing experiences/agents (nimble little products) that use some of the wonderful knowledge available at MSKCC to help the hospital plan for the future, and make good day-to-day decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I've just been getting set up. I've moved into a very nice co-working space in Hackney, and have been getting my desk and micro-office set up. The space overlooks the site of the 2012 Olympic Games, which is currently being redeveloped as a public park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3766/9212353117_ecd0ce2357_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;612&quot; alt=&quot;Olympic Village Recalibration&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I'll finish getting set up. Then, it'll be down to some real work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quickies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I invested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/2&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;, a fabulous text editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B005QVZ79C/ref=oh_details_o00_s00_i02?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;this monitor&lt;/a&gt; for my desk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/paulmayorg/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, despite my queasiness about their terms and conditions. My real photos will still be uploaded to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/paulmmay/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have still not scanned any of the photos I took in May or June.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am taking &lt;a href=&quot;https://class.coursera.org/matrix-001/&quot;&gt;this class&lt;/a&gt; on linear algebra. So far, it's not much fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am 60% of the way through 1Q84.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-1"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/london-weeknotes-1</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Goodbye (For Now) New York</title>
      <published>2013-06-11T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a couple of hours we head to the airport, bound for Costa Rica, then Iceland - a gentle transition out of life in New York to something new. We are moving on after three amazing years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The category of visa we have requires us to leave the US two years, before being eligible to stay for longer. I am not going to riff on the contradictions of the J visa right now, but it's fair to say that we wouldn't leave New York if we didn't have to. We are thriving here, and we both have a lot more to contribute to this great city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We leave behind our places, routines, hobbies, and most importantly - our family, and our wonderful friends. We will miss them all. We know that it's more than possible to stay connected to them from afar, it'll just take a little more work. I am going to try to treat the distance as a fun challenge, and maybe as an opportunity to do some fun projects related to interaction at a distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our destination, at least in the medium term, is London. I'm going to continue working on design projects related to healthcare and computation for Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, and I'm really delighted about this. I love my job. Cliona is looking for opportunities in biotech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I am not at the point where I'm excited about being in a new city, but I'll get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New York, friends and family - thank you so much for a great three years. We love you all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/goodbye-for-now-new-york"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/goodbye-for-now-new-york</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Watson Project at MSKCC</title>
      <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a busy month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've started to make plans for our exit from New York. We've narrowed down the list of European cities where we'd like to live, and have started to look into job opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the exit planning, I've been working on a fascinating new project at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mskcc.org/&quot;&gt;Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team I work with at Sloan-Kettering is working with IBM to train &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-03.ibm.com/innovation/us/watson/index.shtml&quot;&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt;, IBM's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/17/science/17jeopardy-watson.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;machine learning and decision making system&lt;/a&gt;, to diagnose different forms of cancer based on historical medical cases. Once the system has been trained and refined, Watson will be able to recommend appropriate courses of treatment for cancer patients. The project is groundbreaking, and was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/03/the-robot-will-see-you-now/309216/&quot;&gt;recently profiled in the Atlantic:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ari Caroline and his colleagues at Sloan-Kettering are leading Watson's training in cancer care. &quot;You're going to need a tool like Watson,&quot; he says, given the rapidly increasing complexity of the field. (Photo: Kareem Black)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/03/the-robot-will-see-you-now/309216/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/newsroom/img/2013/02/15/watson-meeting.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role on the project is to work with the messier, less structured parts of anonymized medical records, to prepare clean data for the Watson machine learning pipeline. I've also had a little time to work on some of my own experiments involving machine learning and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a real privilege to be involved with the project, and to work with such audaciously intelligent people. I can't wait to get started in the morning, and my thoughts stay with the project long after I leave in the evening (in a good way). I have been spending a lot of my downtime thinking about the intersection of user experience design and different forms of machine learning. I hope to crystallize a few thoughts into blog articles soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/watson-project-sloan-kettering"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/watson-project-sloan-kettering</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>