<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Paul May</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <icon></icon>
  <updated>2016-08-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.paulmay.org/feed.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org"/>
  
    <entry>
      <title>More Audio Feature Extraction</title>
      <published>2016-08-07T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2016-08-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m making incremental progress on &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/audio-information-extraction&quot;&gt;my listening robot project&lt;/a&gt;. The ultimate goal is to build a little machine capable of listening to its surroundings, learning from the sound it hears, and then - later - being able to determine its location based upon what it hears. A reasonable prototype robot might be able to remember 5-10 locations, and then tell those locations apart when asked to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways of approaching the software part of the project. I’ve chosen to go down a classical, supervised machine learning route - extracting features from sound, then using them to fit a machine learning model. In essence, this means taking raw sound, and &lt;em&gt;noticing&lt;/em&gt; particular qualities of the sound. These qualities are associated with a label - say the name of the location - and used to train a machine learning model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work in the last week has been to implement simple feature extraction techniques demonstrated in off-the-shelf audio information extraction libraries Librosa and pyAudioAnalysis. I have been passing in short snippets of music into their feature extraction functions, to output specific features of that sound - &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectral_centroid&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;spectral centroid&lt;/a&gt;; the “brightness of a sound”, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;http://www.ese.wustl.edu/~nehorai/paper/specom03.pdf&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;spectral contrast&lt;/a&gt;; the difference between peaks and valleys in a sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, I’m implementing litte feature extractor classes that can be passed some sound, returning feature representations of the sound. I’m trying to get the structure of this right, up front, so I don’t have a lot of refactoring and noodling to do later. I’m also trying to be somewhat agnostic of the underlying library, so that they can be mixed/swapped as needs be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting close to just piping feature data into some dumb classifier; getting to a crude proof of concept. I’m not sure whether information extraction techniques more geared towards understanding &lt;em&gt;music&lt;/em&gt; are useful for understanding ambient sound - if they’re not, then I may need to adopt another approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/further-feature-extraction"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/further-feature-extraction</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Extracting Information from Sound</title>
      <published>2016-07-31T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m working on a new information retrieval and machine learning project - but unlike previous projects that involved large amounts of text, this project involves sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to create a small, self-contained robot that can listen to, and learn from its surroundings - building up sonic fingerprints of a number of locations. Later, it should be possible for the robot to tell what location it’s at, simply by listening, and comparing it what it hears to previous experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just getting started with the project, and my focus is on writing simple software that can record sound, extract features, fit machine learning models, then classify previously unheard sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field of audio/music information retrieval is very well-developed, so I have a lot to read and learn from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a simple hello-world, I took two existing sound files; a Mozart piano sonata, and a recent track by Rihanna, and visualized them as &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chroma_feature&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;chromagrams&lt;/a&gt;. Visually, the difference between the two tracks is clear, and this might be a clue that the notes used in a piece of music represent useful features for a machine learning model. I’ve yet to discover if this is the case, or if chromatic features are useful for more ambient sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that, for now, I’m foregoing any thought of using deep learning techniques to create vector representations of sound, for use in classification tasks. I might try to tackle this down the road. Crawl, walk, run etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll write up what I find as the project continues.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/audio-information-extraction"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/audio-information-extraction</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Graduation</title>
      <published>2014-09-05T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2014-09-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a very busy, and very important few weeks. Last week I had the great honour to watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.academia.edu/SimonMay&quot;&gt;my brother&lt;/a&gt; graduate from University of Chicago with a PhD in Anthropology. I am so proud of him. It takes a lot of hard work to tackle a complex project spanning many years, but he did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the graduation I spent some time in New York, catching up with the team at Sloan Kettering. Our projects have been challenging, and not without some major bumps in the road, but this week things became simpler, and better. The feedback from the eventual users of our work is very positive. We’re definitely on a fruitful path, and we’ve been given permission to make our work as good as it needs to be. It feels like this week marked the crossing of some important threshold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got to spend some time with my New York friends, who I miss quite a bit. It’s so cool to be able to come back, spend time with them, and hear about all their lives and their work. They’re building new devices, designing interfaces, writing software, building automata, writing about technology, and making all sorts of things work a little better. They are all so eager to learn, make, and understand more. I feel really refreshed and inspired, because of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also this week; &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2014/09/140903-galaxy-supercluster-map-laniakea-astronomy-science-ngspace/&quot;&gt;some perspective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Throughout the universe, galaxies tend to clump together in massive structures that astronomers call superclusters. According to the new map, Earth’s galaxy lives near the edge of the Laniakea supercluster, which measures 500 million light-years in diameter and includes roughly 100,000 galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks, me and Cliona will introduce a new little person into this sea of infinity. I am excited to meet whomever arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/simon-grad-nyc-progress"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/simon-grad-nyc-progress</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Final Year Projects at CIID</title>
      <published>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I had the pleasure of attending some of the final student presentations and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/&quot;&gt;end-of-year show&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ciid.dk&quot;&gt;Copenhagen Institute for Interaction Design&lt;/a&gt;. Here are some of my favourite projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5498/11371288085_dc17139d97_b.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Indie Controls&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;[Indie Controls](http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/indie-controls/): A novel, open-source, modular games controller by Daniel Lahar.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5474/11371288685_808c778bf9_b_d.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Pretotype&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;[Preotype](http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/pretotype/): A toolkit that supports the design and documentation of physical computing and electronics projects.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3832/11371423703_5fb9cc86b8_b_d.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Griphint&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;[Griphint](http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/griphint/): A pen that offers autistic children visual feedback on their pen grip as they learn to write.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3710/11371424183_748030805e_b.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; alt=&quot;Kwerkies&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;[Kwerkies](http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/kwerkies/): Really beautifully designed wooden toys that operate as a network, and react to one another.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also really liked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/hej_verden/&quot;&gt;hej_verden&lt;/a&gt; - A toolkit to help children learn computer programming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/little-treasures/&quot;&gt;Little Treasures&lt;/a&gt; - A thoroughly-designed service designed to teach children about the concept of value and the use of money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ciid.dk/education/portfolio/idp13/courses/final-projects-2013/hand-made/&quot;&gt;Hand Made&lt;/a&gt; - An exploration of human hand gestures, and a platform to collect novel hand gestures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work from CIID students was, as ever, thorough and thoughtful. It’s a great programme.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/ciid-show"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/ciid-show</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Paying for the Web we Need</title>
      <published>2013-12-10T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-12-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I probably reacted to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/edward-snowden&quot;&gt;Edward Snowden&lt;/a&gt; revelations in the same way that a lot of people did. Not with surprise that mass surveillance happens, but that it happens &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/03/world/no-morsel-too-minuscule-for-all-consuming-nsa.html&quot;&gt;so completely and so effectively&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Months later, I’ve factored the revelations into my opinion of how governments tend to behave (&lt;em&gt;slightly more competent, a lot less cautious&lt;/em&gt;), but otherwise, my behaviour remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web that I use, and have helped to build, is one where acceptance of minute surveillance of my activities is a pre-condition for the use of the most basic services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This web has laid the technical foundations for mass surveillance, but I believe that it has also laid the psychological/ethical groundwork for the acceptance of surveillance as just another facet of my daily life. (Why &lt;em&gt;wouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; governments put me under surveillance when I’ve accepted that companies are allowed to, in exchange for keeping track of my friends’ birthdays.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology introduces biases in the types of things it makes more or less easy. Things that are easy become normal. Things that are difficult become other. The Snowden leaks are the clearest demonstration of this at scale. Remaining private is difficult, and so demanding privacy now would disconnect me from the majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly maybe, the leaks show me that technology has drastically skewed my sense of what is acceptable. I can’t help but fit the NSA’s activities into the moral framework I’ve built up around targeted advertising. And they are certainly not equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’d be impractical, and lonely, to move my online life over to services that aren’t funded via surveillance-marketing, but I can take a small step by paying for more parts of the web that I value in cold hard cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can also try to evaluate things that might be technologically similar, but ethically different, with a much more critical eye.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/paying-for-the-web-we-need"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/paying-for-the-web-we-need</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Seamus Heaney - The Underground</title>
      <published>2013-08-30T17:31:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-30T17:31:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leaving is difficult. Moving is difficult. Starting is  difficult. Doing all three at once has been, at times, difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard this today for the first time, to my shame. I thought of Cliona, our journey forward together, and not looking back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;730&quot; height=&quot;411&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/30LR0tIDb3g?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To end up in a draughty lamplit station
After the trains have gone, the wet track
Bared and tensed as I am, all attention
For your step following and damned if I look back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite something.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/heaney-underground"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/heaney-underground</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Red Burns</title>
      <published>2013-08-24T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Red Burns, founder of ITP, and true force of nature, died yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met Red during my impromptu interview for ITP. Cliona and I were visiting New York for just one day. We were engaged, and spent the morning buying our wedding rings in the diamond district. We stopped by ITP for a tour with George Agudow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red heard that I was on the floor, and called me into her office. She asked Cliona to come in too, and found a comfortable chair for her to sit in while we talked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, I’ve read your application and I can’t make head or tail of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any idea that this was going to be a casual chat went out the window. She proceeded to grill me for a solid hour about what I had written, why I wanted to come to ITP, what my ideas were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I didn’t know exactly why I wanted to come to ITP. I was worried that I was becoming a talker and not a doer. I wanted to make things again. I was interested in health and the human body. Instead of just saying that, I had written thousands of words of the worst sort of bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red called me out, and I had very little to say for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, Cliona and I sat quietly eating a slice of pizza in the corner deli. I was grumpy. How dare she do that in front of my future wife!? Maybe ITP wasn’t for me. (Cliona rightly pointed out that I should have expected her to interview me, or at least talk to me, if I was visiting all the way from Ireland).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. I got into ITP. I got to make things again. I got to meet the most wonderful people. I learned and grew more in two years than I had in the previous ten. I got to do all of this thanks to Red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had many more encounters with her over the years. She took an interest in some of my projects, and made sure I talked to the right people about them. She was constantly working to make sure that our work was as good as it could be, and had the maximum impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I start to lose my nerve, or I feel myself drifting into excuses, I think of my interview with Red. I summon some of her clarity, and I get myself back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Burns changed my life. Thank you Red.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/red-burns"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/red-burns</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Watson Project at MSKCC</title>
      <published>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve started to make plans for our exit from New York. We’ve narrowed down the list of European cities where we’d like to live, and have started to look into job opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the exit planning, I’ve been working on a fascinating new project at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mskcc.org/&quot;&gt;Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team I work with at Sloan-Kettering is working with IBM to train &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-03.ibm.com/innovation/us/watson/index.shtml&quot;&gt;Watson&lt;/a&gt;, IBM’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/17/science/17jeopardy-watson.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;machine learning and decision making system&lt;/a&gt;, to diagnose different forms of cancer based on historical medical cases. Once the system has been trained and refined, Watson will be able to recommend appropriate courses of treatment for cancer patients. The project is groundbreaking, and was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/03/the-robot-will-see-you-now/309216/&quot;&gt;recently profiled in the Atlantic:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ari Caroline and his colleagues at Sloan-Kettering are leading Watson’s training in cancer care. “You’re going to need a tool like Watson,” he says, given the rapidly increasing complexity of the field. (Photo: Kareem Black)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/03/the-robot-will-see-you-now/309216/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/newsroom/img/2013/02/15/watson-meeting.jpg&quot; class=&quot;photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role on the project is to work with the messier, less structured parts of anonymized medical records, to prepare clean data for the Watson machine learning pipeline. I’ve also had a little time to work on some of my own experiments involving machine learning and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a real privilege to be involved with the project, and to work with such audaciously intelligent people. I can’t wait to get started in the morning, and my thoughts stay with the project long after I leave in the evening (in a good way). I have been spending a lot of my downtime thinking about the intersection of user experience design and different forms of machine learning. I hope to crystallize a few thoughts into blog articles soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/watson-project-sloan-kettering"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/watson-project-sloan-kettering</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Design Research Talk at the Pratt Institute</title>
      <published>2013-02-04T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight I’m visiting Visual Communication students at the Pratt Institute to give feedback on their assignment “Something Useful”. The students have been asked to: 
&amp;gt; Uncover, research, and visualize the innerworkings of a frequently used system that tends to go unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a cool assignment, and I am looking forward to seeing the students’ progress. I’ll also be giving a brief talk about doing research to inform a design project. Thanks to Pratt instructor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.genalodesigns.com/&quot;&gt;Bobby Genalo&lt;/a&gt; for inviting me along.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/talk-pratt-institute"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/talk-pratt-institute</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Everywhere I Have Ever Lived</title>
      <published>2013-02-03T00:00:00Z</published>
      <updated>2013-02-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’re leaving New York in June, departing for &lt;em&gt;we don’t know where yet&lt;/em&gt;. I can hardly believe that I’m moving again. By my count I’ve lived in 4 cities and approximately 12 houses/apartments in the past decade. This is the first time I’ve actually made a list of those places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8325/8436957984_60f1b30394_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Kilbarrack Road, Dublin&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
My childhood home on Kilbarrack Road in Dublin. There’s just too much to say about this great house. I drifted away slowly over the course of 2004/2005. My Dad sold the house few years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8052/8436956268_39398a9b97_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of East 53rd Street, Hyde Park, Chicago&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In the summer of 2002 I spent 4 months living on East 53rd Street in Hyde Park, Chicago. I couldn’t find a job, and was down to my last few dollars when I happened to bump into some other Irish people who worked at the Adler Planetarium. They recommended me for a job there, and I scraped by for another 2.5 months before heading back to Dublin. A very strange summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8221/8436957516_7c215675b7_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Shanowen Road, Dublin&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
For about three months of 2004 I lived in an apartment on Shanowen Road near DCU. My housemates were Michael Moriarty and Nicky Gallogly. I can’t for the life of me remember how the three of us ended up living together, but it was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8237/8435872435_c071b5b63f_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Glasnevin, Dublin&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
For a very brief period of 2004 or 2005, maybe a couple of months, I lived somewhere in Glasnevin, Dublin. I don’t know the exact address and have incredibly patcy memories of this whole experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8369/8435883069_b8b0abe50d_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Dargle Road, Dublin&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In 2005 I moved into a small house on Dargle Road in Drumcondra.  My housemates were Ciara Gogarty, Aoife McNamara, Eoin Norton, and for a very brief period, Padraig Kilbride. The house was decrepit, the landlord was a spiv, and the dishes were never done, but we had fun there. The incident with the rat wasn’t much fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8226/8435872221_606ab2c1ca_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Booterstown Park, Dublin&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In 2006 I moved to a rather grand house on Booterstown Park; my first foray onto the South Side of Dublin. My housemates were Karl Podesta, Louise Connolly, and Johnny Callaghan. Even though this was a very quiet street in a very quiet area, I really enjoyed living here. My room was huge, the garden was great, the kitchen was great, and everybody did their bit to keep the house in working order. It was a really pleasant experience all round. Not cheap though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8224/8435873423_1451725dee_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Titania Street, Belfast&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In 2007 I quit my wretched job in management consulting and moved to Belfast to work at Front (now part of Monotype). I lived in a little house on Titania Street off the Cregagh Road, first in the attic room, then in a nicer front-facing room. My constantly rotating cast of housemates included Emma, Aasa, Greg, and Mario. They were all very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8463/8435871471_3cb41c70e0_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Rossmore Avenue, Belfast&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In February of 2009 the constantly changing cast of characters at Titania Street, and a desire to be closer to both work and a swimming pool, prompted me to relocate across the city to Rossmore Avenue. My new housemates were Cassie, Breda, Chris, Johann, and for a short time, Emma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8075/8436971692_09286e4923_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Rossmore Avenue, Belfast&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
I spent weekdays in Belfast, but came back to Dublin on weekends to stay with Cliona. I was frequently to be found at her place on Parnell Street. Cliona’s flatmates, Beatriz and then Kate, tolerated me beyond the call of duty and reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8502/8435871615_d9a2009481_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of North Great George&#39;s Street, Dublin&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In September of 2009 I managed to persuade the folks at Front to let me work from Dublin 2 days a week. Me and Cliona rented a really nice basement/garden apartment on North Great George’s Street in Dublin. This is probably the most fabulous place I will ever live. We had a spare bedroom and a huge garden. We are able to have parties without bothering a soul. We spent a happy year here in the run up to our wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8080/8436957678_23eb4605cc_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Sagimor Gardens, Belfast&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In 2009/2010 I was spending 3 nights a week in Belfast, and 4 nights a week in Dublin, so to cut down on costs I moved out of Rossmore Avenue in Belfast and rented a tiny room in a house in East Belfast. The owner of the house, Sarah, was very nice. She was saving up so that she could quit her job and go sailing for a year. I don’t know if she ever went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8093/8435873717_e92f8a68e3_b_d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satellite photo of Ocean Avenue, Brooklyn&quot; class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; /&gt;
In August 2010 I arrived in New York to start at NYU. I spent a couple of weeks staying with Courtney Kelly, but soon found a great apartment on Ocean Avenue in Prospect Leffert Gardens. Cliona arrived in New York a couple of months later, and we are still living on Ocean Avenue 2.5 years later. This really feels like home. I hope, probably in vain, that the next place we live is as good to us as this place has been.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://www.paulmay.org/blog/everywhere-i-have-ever-lived"/>
      <id>http://www.paulmay.org/blog/everywhere-i-have-ever-lived</id>
      <author>
        <name>Paul May</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>